<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-18T15:40:05+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Invisible Parade</title><subtitle>My personal webpage and blog.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A website redesign</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/redesign-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A website redesign" /><published>2025-04-18T14:02:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-04-18T14:02:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/redesign-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/redesign-2025"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve overhauled the design of my website, and am very happy with how it turned out.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="/assets/images/2025/index-redesign.jpg" alt="The root homepage. Old design on the left, new design on the right." class="center-image" />
  <figcaption>The root homepage. Old design on the left, new design on the right.</figcaption>
  </figure>

<figure>
    <img src="/assets/images/2025/dark-redesign.jpg" alt="A post page in dark mode. Old design on the left, new design on the right." class="center-image" style="max-height: 300px;" />
    <figcaption>A post page in dark mode. Old design on the left, new design on the right.</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="design-considerations">Design considerations</h2>

<h3 id="the-structure">The structure</h3>

<p>My first inspiration was the concept of <a href="https://slashpages.net">slash pages</a>, which I love — they are very easy to understand, and have a fun vibe characteristic of simple webpages that are just collections of pages. I wanted to take it a step further, and use the structure of the website as a design feature. The navigation element is arranged like a file system, and the current page’s URL is displayed prominently in the header.</p>

<h3 id="the-colors">The colors</h3>

<p>I used colors from the <a href="https://uchu.style">uchū color palette</a> by <a href="https://webb.page/">Wibby</a>. I love these colors and was waiting for a project to use them in. I can tell that a lot of care went into choosing each shade, and it made handling the dark mode appearance fairly easy.</p>

<p>Which brings me to:</p>

<h3 id="dark-mode">Dark mode</h3>

<p>There is a toggle in the upper-right, but the site will otherwise default to respecting your OS’s preference. I stopped using <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">prefers-color-scheme</code> declarations and instead am using <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">light-dark()</code>, which is fantastic.</p>

<p>I learned about it from <a href="https://css-tricks.com/come-to-the-light-dark-side/">this article</a> by <a href="https://sarajoy.dev">Sara Joy</a>, which explained everything I needed to know and more. I won’t go into too many details here because you should just go read that article, but the main points of my implementation are:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Declare <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">color-scheme: light dark;</code> on <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;html&gt;</code>, to automatically switch themes based on the visitor’s OS.</li>
  <li>Each time I specify a color in the CSS, write it like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">color: light-dark(black, white)</code> to define the color for light mode and dark mode, respectively.</li>
  <li>If the theme toggle is clicked, update <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;html&gt;</code> to be only <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">color-scheme: light</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">color-scheme: dark</code> to lock it into the correct theme.</li>
  <li>Save the chosen theme to the browser’s <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">localStorage</code> to preserve the preference across visits.</li>
</ol>

<p>All of the theme switching is done with Javascript, which has the advantage of creating a good fallback if Javascript is disabled — the default is to simply follow the OS’s preferences. And since the theme toggle button’s icon is drawn by Javascript to reflect the active theme, having no Javascript will render the button blank — which is perfect because it won’t do anything anyways.</p>

<h2 id="thats-all-the-important-things-i-think">That’s all the important things, I think</h2>

<p>You can check out the source code <a href="https://github.com/aonsager/aonsager_built">here</a> if you want to look inside.</p>

<p>Please reach out if something looks broken!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="design" /><category term="website" /><category term="colors" /><category term="theme" /><category term="javascript" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve overhauled the design of my website, and am very happy with how it turned out. The root homepage. Old design on the left, new design on the right. A post page in dark mode. Old design on the left, new design on the right. Design considerations The structure My first inspiration was the concept of slash pages, which I love — they are very easy to understand, and have a fun vibe characteristic of simple webpages that are just collections of pages. I wanted to take it a step further, and use the structure of the website as a design feature. The navigation element is arranged like a file system, and the current page’s URL is displayed prominently in the header. The colors I used colors from the uchū color palette by Wibby. I love these colors and was waiting for a project to use them in. I can tell that a lot of care went into choosing each shade, and it made handling the dark mode appearance fairly easy. Which brings me to: Dark mode There is a toggle in the upper-right, but the site will otherwise default to respecting your OS’s preference. I stopped using prefers-color-scheme declarations and instead am using light-dark(), which is fantastic. I learned about it from this article by Sara Joy, which explained everything I needed to know and more. I won’t go into too many details here because you should just go read that article, but the main points of my implementation are: Declare color-scheme: light dark; on &lt;html&gt;, to automatically switch themes based on the visitor’s OS. Each time I specify a color in the CSS, write it like color: light-dark(black, white) to define the color for light mode and dark mode, respectively. If the theme toggle is clicked, update &lt;html&gt; to be only color-scheme: light or color-scheme: dark to lock it into the correct theme. Save the chosen theme to the browser’s localStorage to preserve the preference across visits. All of the theme switching is done with Javascript, which has the advantage of creating a good fallback if Javascript is disabled — the default is to simply follow the OS’s preferences. And since the theme toggle button’s icon is drawn by Javascript to reflect the active theme, having no Javascript will render the button blank — which is perfect because it won’t do anything anyways. That’s all the important things, I think You can check out the source code here if you want to look inside. Please reach out if something looks broken!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://invisibleparade.com/2025/redesign.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://invisibleparade.com/2025/redesign.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I may have outgrown Coolify</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/outgrowing-coolify" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I may have outgrown Coolify" /><published>2025-04-07T13:35:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-04-07T13:35:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/outgrowing-coolify</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/outgrowing-coolify"><![CDATA[<p>I initially chose <a href="https://coolify.io/">Coolify</a> as a self-hosted alternative to Heroku when it got too expensive. Coolify makes a lot of things very easy, but I ended up having to dig in to the details and learn a lot to fix things that didn’t work. Now that I have learned a fair bit about server management, I’ve found that I may no longer need Coolify’s hand-holding.</p>

<h2 id="venturing-into-self-hosting">Venturing into self-hosting</h2>

<p>I knew next to nothing about Linux servers, Docker, reverse proxies, and the like. I had used Heroku for a long time, but its base price became restrictively expensive considering how small each of my little projects was, so I started looking for a service that could ease me into self-hosting my apps on a VPS.</p>

<p>I started with <a href="https://dokku.com">Dokku</a>, but the lack of a GUI made me uncomfortable because I really had no idea what I was doing. I was running with my eyes closed, hoping I didn’t trip. <a href="https://coolify.io/">Coolify</a> seemed to make deployments easy, and had a lot of handy tools to let me manage all aspects of my services through a web GUI, so I jumped in.</p>

<h2 id="coolify-was-good-until-it-wasnt">Coolify was good, until it wasn’t</h2>

<p>A lot things were very easy! Go to an open-source project’s repository, find a sample Docker Compose file, paste it into a box, and hit “Go”. It handled URLs, SSL certificates, routing, and probably a lot of other things that I wasn’t fully aware of.</p>

<p>But there were plenty of things that did not go so smoothly. In these cases I had to stumble my way to a working solution, learning about what Docker Compose files do, where files are placed on my server, how to install packages that I need, and so on.</p>

<p>When something went wrong with one of my apps, I would SSH into the server’s root and go digging through the files there to figure out what is happening. I learned how different containers are managed on the server, Docker’s command line utilities to ask each container what it is doing, various ways to change settings and reboot apps on the fly.</p>

<h2 id="the-last-battle">The last battle</h2>

<p>My <a href="http://gotosocial.org">GoToSocial</a> <a href="http://gts.invisibleparade.com">instance</a> had a problem where it would randomly become unresponsive once every couple of days. I would realize that everything was timing out, and restarting the service was the only way to get things running again. It took me months of “debugging”, where I would dump out service logs, sift through documentation, and dig into every line of configuration that looked like it might be related to the problem in any way.</p>

<p>At last, I tracked down the problem.</p>

<p>My GoToSocial compose file defined a Docker network called <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gotosocial</code>, as a network is required for the application and the database to communicate with each other. However, because a network is of course required, Coolify <em>conveniently</em> was also defining its own unique network, automatically and behind the scenes. And for some reason, a <em>third</em> network was also being created as the result of some combination of settings (I never did figure out why this was happening).</p>

<p>Of these multiple redundant networks, the GoToSocial application was attached to only two, and the reverse proxy was attached to <em>a different two</em>. Something at some point would trigger some load balancing in the reverse proxy, and it would switch to its second known network, which did not have the application attached. Hence the unresponsiveness.</p>

<p>All I had to do to fix this was to delete the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gotosocial</code> network declaration in the Docker Compose file. But in discovering that solution, I ended learning a lot about how reverse proxies and Docker networks work, and walking around in a lot of code. Now, I feel pretty confident that I would be able to manage Docker-based deploys without Coolify in the middle.</p>

<p>Which brings me to my latest realization.</p>

<h2 id="now-i-can-do-this-myself">Now, I can do this myself</h2>

<p>Coolify does a lot of (most of the time) convenient things behind the scenes, but sometimes they aren’t what I need. To understand what these conveniences are, how to work with them, when they are good and when they are not, and how to change things when I need to, I had to learn a lot about all of the moving parts of a Linux server with multiple docker containers running various services.</p>

<p>Now that I have this experience, it seems like Coolify’s behind-the-scenes actions might be causing more trouble than convenience.</p>

<p>I think I will get myself a fresh new VPN and start trying to replicate my apps with just manual Docker deployments + a simple <a href="https://caddyserver.com">Caddy</a> configuration. Or maybe <a href="https://dokku.com">Dokku</a> again, that’s worth a revisit.</p>

<p>So, thanks to Coolify for bringing me here, but I think our time together will be ending.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="self-hosting" /><category term="docker" /><category term="coolify" /><category term="linux" /><category term="vps" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I initially chose Coolify as a self-hosted alternative to Heroku when it got too expensive. Coolify makes a lot of things very easy, but I ended up having to dig in to the details and learn a lot to fix things that didn’t work. Now that I have learned a fair bit about server management, I’ve found that I may no longer need Coolify’s hand-holding. Venturing into self-hosting I knew next to nothing about Linux servers, Docker, reverse proxies, and the like. I had used Heroku for a long time, but its base price became restrictively expensive considering how small each of my little projects was, so I started looking for a service that could ease me into self-hosting my apps on a VPS. I started with Dokku, but the lack of a GUI made me uncomfortable because I really had no idea what I was doing. I was running with my eyes closed, hoping I didn’t trip. Coolify seemed to make deployments easy, and had a lot of handy tools to let me manage all aspects of my services through a web GUI, so I jumped in. Coolify was good, until it wasn’t A lot things were very easy! Go to an open-source project’s repository, find a sample Docker Compose file, paste it into a box, and hit “Go”. It handled URLs, SSL certificates, routing, and probably a lot of other things that I wasn’t fully aware of. But there were plenty of things that did not go so smoothly. In these cases I had to stumble my way to a working solution, learning about what Docker Compose files do, where files are placed on my server, how to install packages that I need, and so on. When something went wrong with one of my apps, I would SSH into the server’s root and go digging through the files there to figure out what is happening. I learned how different containers are managed on the server, Docker’s command line utilities to ask each container what it is doing, various ways to change settings and reboot apps on the fly. The last battle My GoToSocial instance had a problem where it would randomly become unresponsive once every couple of days. I would realize that everything was timing out, and restarting the service was the only way to get things running again. It took me months of “debugging”, where I would dump out service logs, sift through documentation, and dig into every line of configuration that looked like it might be related to the problem in any way. At last, I tracked down the problem. My GoToSocial compose file defined a Docker network called gotosocial, as a network is required for the application and the database to communicate with each other. However, because a network is of course required, Coolify conveniently was also defining its own unique network, automatically and behind the scenes. And for some reason, a third network was also being created as the result of some combination of settings (I never did figure out why this was happening). Of these multiple redundant networks, the GoToSocial application was attached to only two, and the reverse proxy was attached to a different two. Something at some point would trigger some load balancing in the reverse proxy, and it would switch to its second known network, which did not have the application attached. Hence the unresponsiveness. All I had to do to fix this was to delete the gotosocial network declaration in the Docker Compose file. But in discovering that solution, I ended learning a lot about how reverse proxies and Docker networks work, and walking around in a lot of code. Now, I feel pretty confident that I would be able to manage Docker-based deploys without Coolify in the middle. Which brings me to my latest realization. Now, I can do this myself Coolify does a lot of (most of the time) convenient things behind the scenes, but sometimes they aren’t what I need. To understand what these conveniences are, how to work with them, when they are good and when they are not, and how to change things when I need to, I had to learn a lot about all of the moving parts of a Linux server with multiple docker containers running various services. Now that I have this experience, it seems like Coolify’s behind-the-scenes actions might be causing more trouble than convenience. I think I will get myself a fresh new VPN and start trying to replicate my apps with just manual Docker deployments + a simple Caddy configuration. Or maybe Dokku again, that’s worth a revisit. So, thanks to Coolify for bringing me here, but I think our time together will be ending.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My AI manifesto</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/ai-manifesto" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My AI manifesto" /><published>2025-03-28T16:55:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T16:55:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/ai-manifesto</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/ai-manifesto"><![CDATA[<p>This is my personal manifesto for how I will and will not use generative AI. I believe it can be an extremely useful tool in certain situations, but can also have many negative repurcussions if used incorrectly.</p>

<h2 id="1-use-to-expand-my-abilities-not-as-a-crutch">1: Use to expand my abilities, not as a crutch.</h2>

<h3 id="a-teach-me-new-things">A: Teach me new things</h3>

<p>As a coding assistant, AI can quickly show me the correct syntax. It can suggest implementations, and teach me how to implement new functions. These are extremely useful, and help me to be exponentionally more productive as a hobby developer.</p>

<p>I must take care to use this as a tool to help me learn and grow. Instead of receiving the AI’s solution and calling it done, I need to understand what it has suggested and why, so that next time I will be better able to produce that answer on my own.</p>

<h3 id="b-do-things-i-cant-do">B: Do things I can’t do</h3>

<p>If there is a trivial thing that I actually can’t do, and it is a progress blocker, I will use AI to fill in the gaps in my skill. Drawing a logo image for a silly pet project, creating a colorful, abstract background image, etc. It doesn’t make sense for me to learn how to do that for myself, so I feel comfortable delegating that to AI.</p>

<h3 id="c-dont-do-things-i-can-do">C: Don’t do things I can do</h3>

<p>I do not use AI to write for me. I am able to write for myself, to express my thoughts through words in order to share my ideas with others. I believe that skills deteriorate without practice, and I am afraid of ever losing that ability. I will never delegate my writing, my thinking, and my shaping of ideas.</p>

<h2 id="2-treat-as-a-tool-for-creators-not-as-a-creator-unto-itself">2: Treat as a tool for creators, not as a creator unto itself.</h2>

<p>I work in a very creative, collaborative environment so this is very relevant professionally as well. It’s possible for me have an AI generate ideas, texts, and images, and by doing make me seem self-sufficient without collaborators. I will not do that.</p>

<h3 id="a-help-those-who-create">A: Help those who create</h3>

<p>There are many ways for creative professionals to use AI as a tool within their process. If an artist uses AI somehow to help in the creation of their own art, that feels fine. As above, my hope is that they will use it as a way to expand their capabilities, and not as a crutch.</p>

<h3 id="b-dont-try-to-be-a-creator">B: Don’t try to be a creator</h3>

<p>It feels wrong for a non-artist to generate images using AI and treat it as creative output. If I need visual artwork as part of a product, it will be created by a human creator. AI creations will not replace human creations.</p>

<p>AI can be used as a tool through the creative process, but will not be directly creating any part of the finished product. That is the responsibility of the creators, the people, and is too important to be delegated.</p>

<h3 id="c-help-me-to-collaborate">C: Help me to collaborate</h3>

<p>While I will always value my ability to communicate through words, sometimes an image can be far more efficient. Finding common ground through concept art, such as by generating many sample images to collectively define what is needed, can be a fast way to reach a shared understanding.</p>

<p>The ease of producing many different formats for presenting an idea allows for experimentation in communication, which has possibilities that aren’t even fully explored yet.</p>

<h2 id="corollaries">Corollaries</h2>

<h3 id="1b--2b-do-what-i-cant-do-while-not-replacing-real-creators">1B + 2B: Do what I can’t do, while not replacing real creators</h3>

<p>I will use AI to do things that I cannot do, but I will not treat the AI as a creator. Anything I create that directly uses something generated by AI will be presented as a proof-of-concept. I will not treat it as a finished product.</p>

<p>Anything that I present as a finished product will be ultimately created by people who can take responsibility as creators. Delegating that role to an AI is irresponsible.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="manifesto" /><category term="ai" /><category term="creativity" /><category term="learning" /><category term="responsibility" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is my personal manifesto for how I will and will not use generative AI. I believe it can be an extremely useful tool in certain situations, but can also have many negative repurcussions if used incorrectly. 1: Use to expand my abilities, not as a crutch. A: Teach me new things As a coding assistant, AI can quickly show me the correct syntax. It can suggest implementations, and teach me how to implement new functions. These are extremely useful, and help me to be exponentionally more productive as a hobby developer. I must take care to use this as a tool to help me learn and grow. Instead of receiving the AI’s solution and calling it done, I need to understand what it has suggested and why, so that next time I will be better able to produce that answer on my own. B: Do things I can’t do If there is a trivial thing that I actually can’t do, and it is a progress blocker, I will use AI to fill in the gaps in my skill. Drawing a logo image for a silly pet project, creating a colorful, abstract background image, etc. It doesn’t make sense for me to learn how to do that for myself, so I feel comfortable delegating that to AI. C: Don’t do things I can do I do not use AI to write for me. I am able to write for myself, to express my thoughts through words in order to share my ideas with others. I believe that skills deteriorate without practice, and I am afraid of ever losing that ability. I will never delegate my writing, my thinking, and my shaping of ideas. 2: Treat as a tool for creators, not as a creator unto itself. I work in a very creative, collaborative environment so this is very relevant professionally as well. It’s possible for me have an AI generate ideas, texts, and images, and by doing make me seem self-sufficient without collaborators. I will not do that. A: Help those who create There are many ways for creative professionals to use AI as a tool within their process. If an artist uses AI somehow to help in the creation of their own art, that feels fine. As above, my hope is that they will use it as a way to expand their capabilities, and not as a crutch. B: Don’t try to be a creator It feels wrong for a non-artist to generate images using AI and treat it as creative output. If I need visual artwork as part of a product, it will be created by a human creator. AI creations will not replace human creations. AI can be used as a tool through the creative process, but will not be directly creating any part of the finished product. That is the responsibility of the creators, the people, and is too important to be delegated. C: Help me to collaborate While I will always value my ability to communicate through words, sometimes an image can be far more efficient. Finding common ground through concept art, such as by generating many sample images to collectively define what is needed, can be a fast way to reach a shared understanding. The ease of producing many different formats for presenting an idea allows for experimentation in communication, which has possibilities that aren’t even fully explored yet. Corollaries 1B + 2B: Do what I can’t do, while not replacing real creators I will use AI to do things that I cannot do, but I will not treat the AI as a creator. Anything I create that directly uses something generated by AI will be presented as a proof-of-concept. I will not treat it as a finished product. Anything that I present as a finished product will be ultimately created by people who can take responsibility as creators. Delegating that role to an AI is irresponsible.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Photo Composition Challenge</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/the-compo-challenge" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Photo Composition Challenge" /><published>2025-03-24T20:56:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T20:56:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/the-compo-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/the-compo-challenge"><![CDATA[<p>I am a mediocre photographer at best, but of course I want to improve. When I saw that <a href="https://social.lol/@hiro">@hiro</a> was putting together 5-week challenge to experiment with various compositional techniques and share our photos, I had to join.</p>

<p>I don’t have fancy gear, or a lot of time to go hunting for photos, so almost all of my shots were scenes from my daily life, taken with an iPhone. I realized pretty quickly though, that being deliberate about composition gave a new perspective on even familiar scenes, and I was surprised at compelling some of the photos turned out.</p>

<!-- more -->

<h2 id="week-1-the-rule-of-thirds">Week 1: The Rule of Thirds</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>The Rule of Thirds challenge is all about getting your subject out of the middle of the frame.
Imagine your frame is divided into three equal segments from left to right, and then again from top to bottom, creating a 3×3 grid. Try to place your subject along one of the lines dividing the thirds, so it’s not squarely in the middle third.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This was a rule I was aware of! I even had the overlay turned on in my Camera app to divide the view into thirds, so now I just need to be deliberate about the positioning.</p>

<h3 id="my-photos">My photos</h3>

<div class="gallery">
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-1" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JMDQSPTHFEZPCGZ5ARKRVW4D.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JMDQSPTHFEZPCGZ5ARKRVW4D.jpeg" alt="A large Pikachu doll standing in front of our children’s bookshelf." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-1" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JMKAPKEJP5JAPK77GRYXX0Y5.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JMKAPKEJP5JAPK77GRYXX0Y5.jpeg" alt="A black pot in the foreground, filled with cabbage, potatoes, carrots, and cherry tomatoes. Various potted plants are visible in the background." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-1" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JMPA2M7FP560PQE4PWVK4N13.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JMPA2M7FP560PQE4PWVK4N13.jpeg" alt="A woven wall tapestry showing the words &quot;hello sunshine&quot; and a rising orange sun. The wallpaper behind is a matching orange color." />
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

<p>The third photo here is my favorite. It is from our kids’ bedroom, and I’m happy that I was able to capture it like this.</p>

<h2 id="week-2-leading-and-diagonal-lines">Week 2: Leading and Diagonal Lines</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>Leading lines are lines within the frame of your shot that naturally draw the viewer’s eye to your subject.
Diagonal lines [. . .] create a sense of movement and tension [. . . and] can also enhance depth, adding a more three-dimensional quality to your composition.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This may have been my favorite exercise. I learned that I really like the aesthetic of leading lines, but unfortunately couldn’t find many good subjects myself. This will be something that I will continue to look out for!</p>

<h3 id="my-photos-1">My photos</h3>

<div class="gallery">
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-2" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JN2MVG4J1HKR6WNBH78YQ3VB.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JN2MVG4J1HKR6WNBH78YQ3VB.jpeg" alt="A covered walkway with concrete columns leads alongside a grassy courtyard filled with bamboo plants. Sunlight casts intricate shadows on the tiled pathway. A modern building with large windows frames the background." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-2" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JN2MVKF1AJR4QX6T406N8QPX.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JN2MVKF1AJR4QX6T406N8QPX.jpeg" alt="A corridor with a tiled floor casts diagonal shadows from a slatted fence on the left. A wooden bench with a black metal frame is on the right. In the background, there is a staircase leading upwards. Sunlight illuminates the scene, and some plants are visible along the left wall." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-2" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JN2MVQ3QFWCHQVMC0RYM30RN.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JN2MVQ3QFWCHQVMC0RYM30RN.jpeg" alt="Low-angle view of two modern buildings with reflective glass surfaces set against a cloudy sky. The buildings create a sharp, angular perspective converging towards the center of the image. Subtle patterns can be seen on the facade of the left building, with both structures appearing dark and sleek." />
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

<p>I like the third photo here, again. I thought it would be neat to get a thin view of the sky between two tall buildings, and found the perfect spot. Then I spun the picture around in an editing app to find just the right claustrophobic angle.</p>

<h2 id="week-3-frame-within-a-frame">Week 3: Frame Within A Frame</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>Whereas Leading Lines used lines within your photo to point to the subject, this technique asks you to find ways to create a frame around your subject in your composition</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I had a hard time finding good subjects again, and 2/3 of my frames ended up just being long corridors. But they are cool shots!</p>

<h3 id="my-photos-2">My photos</h3>

<div class="gallery">
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-3" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JNWBTHMYMC9N1QHDD9Y4272Q.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JNWBTHMYMC9N1QHDD9Y4272Q.jpeg" alt="A young child wearing a cap and dark jacket stands near a white U-shaped barrier with orange stripes, holding a colorful mesh bag. A tennis ball lies on the pavement in front of the barrier. In the background, there is a white van parked beside a residential building on a cloudy day." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-3" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JNWBV55A8BDNGQNKXDZFC6SV.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JNWBV55A8BDNGQNKXDZFC6SV.jpeg" alt="A long, covered walkway with a wooden slatted roof and metal supports stretches between two buildings. The floor is paved with square tiles, and there are small plants lining the right side with gravel. The scene leads to an open area where two people are seen in the distance." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-3" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JNWBVYTFGT15B4BKF3WYQ0G4.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JNWBVYTFGT15B4BKF3WYQ0G4.jpeg" alt="A covered walkway with a dark ceiling and walls leads to an urban street. The path has textured flooring, with tactile paving lines. To the left, there's a small planted area. Outside, a parked car and buildings are visible, with sunlight illuminating the exit." />
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

<h2 id="week-4-subject-isolation--contrast">Week 4: Subject Isolation + Contrast</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>[Contrast] could be very visual by putting a brightly lit subject against a dark background, or color based by contrasting a bright red rose against green foliage, or even conceptual with something like capturing someone who is clearly quite happy on a bus surrounded by dour fellow passengers.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I was surprised that this exercise was the hardest for me. I tried not to rely on just using bokeh to highlight the subject, and it was hard to find things that just naturally stood out from their surroundings. Not only was I tardy in finishing this week, I only managed to take two photos that I was happy with. So it goes.</p>

<div class="gallery">
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-4" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JPVQ73XJHM9MNRZET49RDBZJ.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JPVQ73XJHM9MNRZET49RDBZJ.jpeg" alt="A small giraffe figurine is nestled among vibrant green houseplants on a windowsill. The giraffe has a brown and white pattern, standing out against the lush leaves." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-4" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JPVQ7A2X1HG15046B5BYYYMV.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JPVQ7A2X1HG15046B5BYYYMV.jpeg" alt="A playground with a red and blue slide is in the left foreground. My shadow extends onto the dry grass. A clear blue sky with a few clouds is visible above, with a utility pole and wires in the distance." />
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

<h2 id="week-5-the-golden-spiral">Week 5: The Golden Spiral</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>[The Golden Spiral is] about arranging the elements in your photos along the lines of an imaginary spiral, so that it offers an easy and natural flow for the viewer to follow those elements to your subject.</p>
</blockquote>

<figure>
  <img src="/assets/images/2025/golden_spiral.png" alt="The Golden Spiral" class="center-image" />
  <figcaption>The Golden Spiral</figcaption>
  </figure>

<p>In practice, this ended up being an exercise in imagination as much as photography, as finding subjects that lined up to this mathematically perfect spiral was pretty challenging.</p>

<h3 id="my-photos-3">My photos</h3>

<div class="gallery">
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-5" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JQ2TAR656RZC91ANX3Y75WW8.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JQ2TAR656RZC91ANX3Y75WW8.jpeg" alt="A building with a modern design features dark vertical panels and large windows. In the foreground, a tree with pink blossoms is in full bloom. The sky is mostly clear with a few fluffy clouds, and the sun is shining brightly behind the branches." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-5" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JQ2TBNGMZ9H2SCTJ65Z26SW5.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JQ2TBNGMZ9H2SCTJ65Z26SW5.jpeg" alt="A child wearing a light-colored cap, dark jacket, and jeans slides down a curved, green double slide at a playground. A bright blue sky and a building are visible in the distance." />
        </a>
    </div>
    <div>
        <a data-lightbox="compo-week-5" href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/original/01JQ2TCWT14471HDGA25H20D7K.jpeg">
            <img src="https://gts.invisibleparade.com/fileserver/01GH6B64M32N9Y4742YPSN8KAY/attachment/small/01JQ2TCWT14471HDGA25H20D7K.jpeg" alt="People are enjoying a spinning amusement park ride designed like spaceships. The ride has multiple colorful cars, with &quot;SPACESHIP 10&quot; written on a red car. The sky is clear and blue, with trees and a building visible in the background." />
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

<p>The spaceship photo is probably the one that follows the spiral the closest, and the your eyes naturally flow in the same direction, too. The photo itself could have been better, but that’s what learning is for.</p>

<h2 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h2>

<p>And that’s all! Thank you a hundred times to Hiro for organizing this! I had a wonderful time taking photos, as well as seeing everyone else’s submissions. If there is a next time, I will definitely be joining again.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="photography" /><category term="composition" /><category term="techniques" /><category term="improvement" /><category term="challenge" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am a mediocre photographer at best, but of course I want to improve. When I saw that @hiro was putting together 5-week challenge to experiment with various compositional techniques and share our photos, I had to join. I don’t have fancy gear, or a lot of time to go hunting for photos, so almost all of my shots were scenes from my daily life, taken with an iPhone. I realized pretty quickly though, that being deliberate about composition gave a new perspective on even familiar scenes, and I was surprised at compelling some of the photos turned out.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Python script failing via cron</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/python-cron" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Python script failing via cron" /><published>2025-02-26T15:11:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T15:11:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/python-cron</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/python-cron"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-issue">The issue</h2>

<p>I had setup a cron task to run my <a href="/2025/01/09/squirrel-archive-webpages-so-i-can-find-them-again.html">Squirrel Archiver</a> script once per day, but for some reason the task was not executing. Nothing, including any errors, was showing up in any logs. At first I thought there was something wrong with my crontab, but other scripts set up to run in the same way were running without issue.</p>

<p>Copying the commands in crontab to the terminal and running it manually worked. It was only when cron was triggering the run that it failed.</p>

<p>Just to be sure, I changed my script to just <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">print('hey')</code>, and this worked! So there must have been something wrong inside the script, and I started the tried and true debugging process of <em>deleting chunks of code until something works</em>.</p>

<p>Side note: Since the script had to run via cron, while I was debugging it was set to run once per minute on the dot. I had to rush to make changes in time, but I also had to wait to see results, which made for an interesting experience.</p>

<h2 id="the-culprit">The culprit</h2>

<p>I had been declaring <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">openai_client = OpenAI()</code> as a global variable, outside of any function. This worked fine when running the script manually, but when cron triggered it, it failed silently.</p>

<p>“<em>Why?</em>”<br />
I have no idea.</p>

<p>“<em>Is initializing objects outside of functions commonly known to be a bad practice?</em>”<br />
Probably.</p>

<p>I wish I knew more about the reasons, but moving the declaration inside a function fixed the issue.</p>

<p>So, maybe to many it is obvious that “<em>yes of course you shouldn’t do that</em>”, but I’m recording it here in case anybody else out there is like me.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="cron" /><category term="debugging" /><category term="python" /><category term="scripting" /><category term="bestpractices" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The issue I had setup a cron task to run my Squirrel Archiver script once per day, but for some reason the task was not executing. Nothing, including any errors, was showing up in any logs. At first I thought there was something wrong with my crontab, but other scripts set up to run in the same way were running without issue. Copying the commands in crontab to the terminal and running it manually worked. It was only when cron was triggering the run that it failed. Just to be sure, I changed my script to just print('hey'), and this worked! So there must have been something wrong inside the script, and I started the tried and true debugging process of deleting chunks of code until something works. Side note: Since the script had to run via cron, while I was debugging it was set to run once per minute on the dot. I had to rush to make changes in time, but I also had to wait to see results, which made for an interesting experience. The culprit I had been declaring openai_client = OpenAI() as a global variable, outside of any function. This worked fine when running the script manually, but when cron triggered it, it failed silently. “Why?” I have no idea. “Is initializing objects outside of functions commonly known to be a bad practice?” Probably. I wish I knew more about the reasons, but moving the declaration inside a function fixed the issue. So, maybe to many it is obvious that “yes of course you shouldn’t do that”, but I’m recording it here in case anybody else out there is like me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m doing /now</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/what-im-doing-now" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m doing /now" /><published>2025-02-13T14:34:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T14:34:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/what-im-doing-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/what-im-doing-now"><![CDATA[<h2 id="personal-life">Personal Life</h2>

<p>Nothing much has changed for our family these past few years, and that is by design. Work is stable, life is stable, everybody is happy. I am very thankful for that.</p>

<h2 id="work">Work</h2>

<p>Since 2022 I have been leading a department that is tasked with making our studio better at creating new games. This involves encouraging all staff to submit game ideas at any time, working with people to strengthen game ideas and create attractive pitches, coaching teams through early development phases, maintaining a corporate strategy for the release of new games, and more. It allows me to work directly with a lot of people throughout the company, and has been tremendously fun.</p>

<h2 id="hobbies">Hobbies</h2>

<p>In 2022 I joined a Haiku study group. We decide on a few prompts every month and submit our poems in advance of a meet-up, where we comment on each other’s pieces and have our teacher critique them. Haiku is fascinating because its extreme minimalism (only 17 characters allowed) makes it feel like putting together a puzzle. It is also a great way to learn about nature and Japanese culture.</p>

<p>Last year I set up <a href="https://gotosocial.org">GoToSocial</a> as a <a href="https://gts.invisibleparade.com">solo instance</a> to join the Fediverse, and that has been a lot of fun. It’s nice to be social on the internet again. I think this has helped motivate me to update this site more, and I’m having a lot of fun making little updates to the site as well.</p>

<p>AI tools have been super useful for programming as a hobby. It has made it so much easier to finish and ship my little <a href="/projects">projects</a>, and I have already developed a slew of little utilities that I use often. I’m still writing words by hand though, because I think being able to organize my thoughts into communicative sentences is such an important skill.</p>

<p>I also started keeping a physical journal at the beginning of this year, and one month is the longest I have ever kept up the habit so I am hopeful that it will continue. I had always admired people who keep physical journals; I thought it was a wonderful habit. I never could get into it though, and had resigned myself to thinking that I just wasn’t that kind of person. But my wife convinced me that if that is the kind of person I <em>want</em> to be, then it’s worth putting in the effort to make the change.<br />
So far, I am really enjoying it. I’m using the most simple interpretation of <a href="https://bulletjournal.com">Bullet Journal</a>. It’s turning to be a super helpful framework to guide the kinds of information I should keep, and the format for recording it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="parenting" /><category term="preschool" /><category term="technology" /><category term="hobbies" /><category term="journaling" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Personal Life Nothing much has changed for our family these past few years, and that is by design. Work is stable, life is stable, everybody is happy. I am very thankful for that. Work Since 2022 I have been leading a department that is tasked with making our studio better at creating new games. This involves encouraging all staff to submit game ideas at any time, working with people to strengthen game ideas and create attractive pitches, coaching teams through early development phases, maintaining a corporate strategy for the release of new games, and more. It allows me to work directly with a lot of people throughout the company, and has been tremendously fun. Hobbies In 2022 I joined a Haiku study group. We decide on a few prompts every month and submit our poems in advance of a meet-up, where we comment on each other’s pieces and have our teacher critique them. Haiku is fascinating because its extreme minimalism (only 17 characters allowed) makes it feel like putting together a puzzle. It is also a great way to learn about nature and Japanese culture. Last year I set up GoToSocial as a solo instance to join the Fediverse, and that has been a lot of fun. It’s nice to be social on the internet again. I think this has helped motivate me to update this site more, and I’m having a lot of fun making little updates to the site as well. AI tools have been super useful for programming as a hobby. It has made it so much easier to finish and ship my little projects, and I have already developed a slew of little utilities that I use often. I’m still writing words by hand though, because I think being able to organize my thoughts into communicative sentences is such an important skill. I also started keeping a physical journal at the beginning of this year, and one month is the longest I have ever kept up the habit so I am hopeful that it will continue. I had always admired people who keep physical journals; I thought it was a wonderful habit. I never could get into it though, and had resigned myself to thinking that I just wasn’t that kind of person. But my wife convinced me that if that is the kind of person I want to be, then it’s worth putting in the effort to make the change. So far, I am really enjoying it. I’m using the most simple interpretation of Bullet Journal. It’s turning to be a super helpful framework to guide the kinds of information I should keep, and the format for recording it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Katamari Damacy postmortem</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/katamari-damacy-postmortem" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Katamari Damacy postmortem" /><link href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/postmortem-the-singular-design-of-namco-s-katamari-damacy-2004-" rel="related" type="text/html" title="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/postmortem-the-singular-design-of-namco-s-katamari-damacy-2004-" /><published>2025-02-12T11:48:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T11:48:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/katamari-damacy-postmortem</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/katamari-damacy-postmortem"><![CDATA[<p>By Game Developer Magazine:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We recently received a request to publish the Katamari Damacy postmortem from the December 2004 issue of Game Developer. It has been posted here in full for the first time in 2024 to celebrate the game’s 20 year anniversary. Please enjoy.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This article was written by the game’s director, Keita Takahashi, and has been translated into English from the original Japanese. I wish I could find the original text, but this is a great read regardless.</p>

<p>It’s easy to take a successful game and say “Here are its unique features and the reasons why we think they led to success.” But this portmortem also includes regrets from the game’s development, which gives a really rare, close look into what the team’s ambitions were and how they thought about the game’s design.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="game" /><category term="developer" /><category term="postmortem" /><category term="katamari" /><category term="anniversary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Game Developer Magazine: We recently received a request to publish the Katamari Damacy postmortem from the December 2004 issue of Game Developer. It has been posted here in full for the first time in 2024 to celebrate the game’s 20 year anniversary. Please enjoy. This article was written by the game’s director, Keita Takahashi, and has been translated into English from the original Japanese. I wish I could find the original text, but this is a great read regardless. It’s easy to take a successful game and say “Here are its unique features and the reasons why we think they led to success.” But this portmortem also includes regrets from the game’s development, which gives a really rare, close look into what the team’s ambitions were and how they thought about the game’s design.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CrossPooter - Poot your toots around the web</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/crosspooter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CrossPooter - Poot your toots around the web" /><published>2025-02-07T16:57:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-02-07T16:57:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/crosspooter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/crosspooter"><![CDATA[<figure>
  <img src="/assets/images/projects/crosspooter.jpeg" alt="CrossPooter logo, showing a smiling cartoon face among arrows branching away" class="center-image" />
  <figcaption>CrossPooter logo, showing a smiling cartoon face among arrows branching away</figcaption>
  </figure>

<p>CrossPooter is a simple script for personal use, that reads the RSS feed of this website and posts the latest article to GoToSocial and Bluesky. It was inspired by <a href="https://echofeed.app">EchoFeed</a>, but I wanted to try my hand at making something similar myself.</p>

<p>You can see the <a href="https://github.com/aonsager/crosspooter">source code here</a>.</p>

<h2 id="features">Features</h2>

<p>CrossPooter reads the RSS feed of this website and checks if the latest article has been posted yet. If not, it will grab the article’s OpenGraph tags to construct a post.</p>

<p>The post will include a link to the article, the article’s title, and the article’s description. It will also attach an image if one is available.</p>

<p>The script is inteded to be run via cron every hour or so. I’m assuming that I won’t be posting new articles faster than that, so the script only checks the latest article.</p>

<h2 id="things-i-learned-building-this">Things I learned building this</h2>

<p>Bluesky was very straightforward since I just used the <a href="https://atproto.blue/en/latest/">official python sdk</a>. GoToSocial probably would have worked with the <a href="https://mastodonpy.readthedocs.io/en/stable/">Maston library</a>, but the API was simple enough that I wanted to try just sending HTTP requests.</p>

<p>I’m still very inexperienced when it comes to creating complex HTTP requests, so I stumbled a lot with setting the correct headers and formatting the data in the correct way. But it was a good exercise in reading source code and documentation, and now I have a stronger handle on how to do it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="crosspooter" /><category term="rss" /><category term="gotosocial" /><category term="bluesky" /><category term="script" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CrossPooter logo, showing a smiling cartoon face among arrows branching away CrossPooter is a simple script for personal use, that reads the RSS feed of this website and posts the latest article to GoToSocial and Bluesky. It was inspired by EchoFeed, but I wanted to try my hand at making something similar myself. You can see the source code here. Features CrossPooter reads the RSS feed of this website and checks if the latest article has been posted yet. If not, it will grab the article’s OpenGraph tags to construct a post. The post will include a link to the article, the article’s title, and the article’s description. It will also attach an image if one is available. The script is inteded to be run via cron every hour or so. I’m assuming that I won’t be posting new articles faster than that, so the script only checks the latest article. Things I learned building this Bluesky was very straightforward since I just used the official python sdk. GoToSocial probably would have worked with the Maston library, but the API was simple enough that I wanted to try just sending HTTP requests. I’m still very inexperienced when it comes to creating complex HTTP requests, so I stumbled a lot with setting the correct headers and formatting the data in the correct way. But it was a good exercise in reading source code and documentation, and now I have a stronger handle on how to do it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://invisibleparade.com/projects/crosspooter.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://invisibleparade.com/projects/crosspooter.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The geometric nests of the white-spotted pufferfish</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/the-geometric-nests-of-the-white-spotted-pufferfish" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The geometric nests of the white-spotted pufferfish" /><link href="https://amami-horizon.com/en/nature/ocean/amami-hoshizorafugu" rel="related" type="text/html" title="https://amami-horizon.com/en/nature/ocean/amami-hoshizorafugu" /><published>2025-02-04T14:25:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-02-04T14:25:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/the-geometric-nests-of-the-white-spotted-pufferfish</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/the-geometric-nests-of-the-white-spotted-pufferfish"><![CDATA[<p>The white-spotted pufferfish, or Amami hoshizora fugu, is a species of pufferfish newly discovered in 2014 near Japan’s Amami-Oshima Island. The males spend roughly a week constructing an elaborate circular nest about 2 meters in diameter to attract females.</p>

<p>Divers had known about these structures that appear in early summer every year, but apparently it took a while to catch the fish in action.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="/assets/images/2025/whitespottedpuffer_nest.jpg" alt="The circular nest of the white-spotted pufferfish" class="center-image" />
  <figcaption>The circular nest of the white-spotted pufferfish</figcaption>
  </figure>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="pufferfish" /><category term="discovery" /><category term="nesting" /><category term="japan" /><category term="marine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The white-spotted pufferfish, or Amami hoshizora fugu, is a species of pufferfish newly discovered in 2014 near Japan’s Amami-Oshima Island. The males spend roughly a week constructing an elaborate circular nest about 2 meters in diameter to attract females. Divers had known about these structures that appear in early summer every year, but apparently it took a while to catch the fish in action. The circular nest of the white-spotted pufferfish]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://invisibleparade.com/2025/whitespottedpuffer_nest.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://invisibleparade.com/2025/whitespottedpuffer_nest.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hobbies that I am no good at</title><link href="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/hobbies-that-i-am-no-good-at" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hobbies that I am no good at" /><published>2025-01-30T14:48:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T14:48:00+09:00</updated><id>https://invisibleparade.com/posts/hobbies-that-i-am-no-good-at</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://invisibleparade.com/posts/hobbies-that-i-am-no-good-at"><![CDATA[<p>A distinguished actor appeared on TV and talked about their love for juggling. They had taken lessons at various times and always sets aside time to practice because they enjoy it so much. They then recounted how they recently met their juggling teacher of ~10 years past, displayed their current juggling skills, and was met with astonishment at how <em>they had not improved one bit in all that time!</em></p>

<p>It was a funny story, but what struck me was just how <em>nice</em> it was that juggling was a constant source of enjoyment for this person <em>despite apparently being no good at it</em>. That’s a hard thing to do.</p>

<p>I think that the internet is partly to blame, since the entire world’s top talent is now at our fingertips. It is too easy to see the best of the best, compare ourselves to them, and end up thinking, “Well what is the point of <em>me</em> doing this at all, then?”</p>

<p>But we must allow ourselves to enjoy things, even in the face of our clear mediocrity. Is there anything I enjoy doing – and let myself enjoy – that I am not good at? Am I denying myself of any hobbies just because of a lack of skill? Let’s dig in.</p>

<h2 id="hobby-web-development">Hobby: Web development</h2>

<p>This one is tricky, because I used to be decent at it but am now well behind the curve. I can slap together some HTML + CSS + JavaScript and make an OK web page. I was adept at Ruby on Rails 10 years ago and can still fuddle through making a web app.</p>

<p>But I touched python for the first time last year. I used Docker for basically the first time last year. I have no idea how to fix a Linux server when things don’t go exactly according to Getting Started guides. I have never touched a JavaScript framework. I have a small comfort-zone and am totally lost outside of it.</p>

<p>These things don’t bother me though, because I enjoy the time I spend tinkering. Occasionally I decide I want to try something new, and I stumble and fumble my through it and maybe learn a little along the way. This is possibly the only creative activity that I can enjoy in a pure, <em>for the love of the craft</em> kind of way. I like that.</p>

<h2 id="not-yet-a-hobby-drawing">Not-yet-a-Hobby: Drawing</h2>

<p>Sometimes I get a hankering to draw a picture, and I always enjoy the time I spend doing it. But I am not a good artist. I’m especially terrible at drawing faces. Awful.</p>

<p>I can’t call it a hobby, since I rarely make time to draw. I have a suspicion that I would enjoy it if I let myself, and that the main thing holding me back is that I think I’m no good at it.</p>

<h2 id="hobby-haiku">Hobby: Haiku</h2>

<p>A few years ago I developed an interest in Haiku. The hyper-minimal structure makes it so that changing just one preposition, or modifying the word order a little, can have a huge impact on the poem’s overall meaning and impact. I think that’s fascinating.</p>

<p>I was lucky to find a group of people that meet regularly for Haiku. We decide on a few prompts, spend a month writing 3 Haiku each, and come together to comment on each other’s pieces and have our teacher critique us.</p>

<p>I think that I’m not <em>bad</em> at Haiku, but to be honest, I thought that I would’ve gotten a little better at it by now. This isn’t discouraging though, as I find myself not really caring how skillful I am. The exercise of distilling a scene to its barest core and painting its picture with my words is <em>fun</em>. I feel like there are some low-hanging fruits for improvement if I put more effort into study, but I’m pretty happy just puttering along at my own pace.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="actor" /><category term="juggling" /><category term="hobby" /><category term="creativity" /><category term="enjoyment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A distinguished actor appeared on TV and talked about their love for juggling. They had taken lessons at various times and always sets aside time to practice because they enjoy it so much. They then recounted how they recently met their juggling teacher of ~10 years past, displayed their current juggling skills, and was met with astonishment at how they had not improved one bit in all that time! It was a funny story, but what struck me was just how nice it was that juggling was a constant source of enjoyment for this person despite apparently being no good at it. That’s a hard thing to do. I think that the internet is partly to blame, since the entire world’s top talent is now at our fingertips. It is too easy to see the best of the best, compare ourselves to them, and end up thinking, “Well what is the point of me doing this at all, then?” But we must allow ourselves to enjoy things, even in the face of our clear mediocrity. Is there anything I enjoy doing – and let myself enjoy – that I am not good at? Am I denying myself of any hobbies just because of a lack of skill? Let’s dig in. Hobby: Web development This one is tricky, because I used to be decent at it but am now well behind the curve. I can slap together some HTML + CSS + JavaScript and make an OK web page. I was adept at Ruby on Rails 10 years ago and can still fuddle through making a web app. But I touched python for the first time last year. I used Docker for basically the first time last year. I have no idea how to fix a Linux server when things don’t go exactly according to Getting Started guides. I have never touched a JavaScript framework. I have a small comfort-zone and am totally lost outside of it. These things don’t bother me though, because I enjoy the time I spend tinkering. Occasionally I decide I want to try something new, and I stumble and fumble my through it and maybe learn a little along the way. This is possibly the only creative activity that I can enjoy in a pure, for the love of the craft kind of way. I like that. Not-yet-a-Hobby: Drawing Sometimes I get a hankering to draw a picture, and I always enjoy the time I spend doing it. But I am not a good artist. I’m especially terrible at drawing faces. Awful. I can’t call it a hobby, since I rarely make time to draw. I have a suspicion that I would enjoy it if I let myself, and that the main thing holding me back is that I think I’m no good at it. Hobby: Haiku A few years ago I developed an interest in Haiku. The hyper-minimal structure makes it so that changing just one preposition, or modifying the word order a little, can have a huge impact on the poem’s overall meaning and impact. I think that’s fascinating. I was lucky to find a group of people that meet regularly for Haiku. We decide on a few prompts, spend a month writing 3 Haiku each, and come together to comment on each other’s pieces and have our teacher critique us. I think that I’m not bad at Haiku, but to be honest, I thought that I would’ve gotten a little better at it by now. This isn’t discouraging though, as I find myself not really caring how skillful I am. The exercise of distilling a scene to its barest core and painting its picture with my words is fun. I feel like there are some low-hanging fruits for improvement if I put more effort into study, but I’m pretty happy just puttering along at my own pace.]]></summary></entry></feed>